Adebanjo, Oluwafemi Peter

Full Stack Developer

11 Ikija Street, Shomolu Lagos, Nigeria | 08095178904 adebanjopete@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Diligent and creative full-stack developer with 10+ years of experience in designing and implementing attractive, user-friendly and functional websites and web applications. Certified and proficient expert with a diverse skill-set and a comprehensive understanding of front-end and back-end technologies. Highly motivated professional who is able to work with a team of excellent technology experts to build cutting edge solutions. Relentless problem solver committed to studying, analyzing and providing creative solutions. Fast learner with the ability to quickly assimilate new ideas and communicate clearly and effectively.

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- PHP
- Laravel
- Angular
- React.js
- Next.js
- Node.js
- Vue.JS
- TypeScript

- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS
- Apollo Client
- GraphQL
- Ionic Framework
- Azure
- AWS Amplify
- Firebase
- WordPress
- Windows Forms
- Doctrine ORM
- DevExpress Winforms

- C#
- Visual Basic [.Net] (VB.Net)
- E-Commerce
- Git
- OOP
- Google Analytics
- SEO
- Hosting
- Deployment
- Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Premiere Pro)

EMPLOYMENT & EXPERIENCE

WEBPRO MEDIA Lagos, Nigeria

Freelance Full Stack Developer

MERN Stack Job Board Admin Application

Link: https://jobber-react.vercel.app/

The back-end server uses Node.js and Express. It exports REST APIs and interacts with MongoDB Database using Mongoose ODM for CRUD operations.

https://github.com/peterdez/jobber-api

React.js Frontend with Redux Toolkit: It consumes the Rest API, displays and modifies jobs data with React Router, Axios & Bootstrap. React Client sends HTTP Requests and retrieves HTTP Responses using Axios, consumes data on the components.

https://github.com/peterdez/jobber-react

NodeJs + Express + MongoDB API

https://github.com/peterdez/nodejs-users-app

Built a NodeJs + Express + MongoDB API that can persist, edit, and retrieve user information. The API allows the caller to persist either one or more users, fetch an existing user by their userID, edit an existing user by their userID, as well as fetch all the users who've been persisted so far.

Laravel Gigs Application

https://github.com/peterdez/laravel-gigs

Built an application for managing "Gigs". A Gig is a single professional engagement, usually of short duration.

I converted the user interface design made by the design team into a live project, implementing CRUD operations for managing "Gigs" using Bootstrap and the Laravel framework.

PHP CSV Importer:

https://github.com/peterdez/csv-importer

Developed a PHP web application that allows users to import countries and currencies database form CSV to a MySQL database. Created an API endpoint to return the countries and currencies dataset with pagination. Implemented a live search feature with AJAX whereby data is fetched from the database and results are shown as the user types in the search field and result narrow as the user continues to type.

ReactNodeJS Insurance

https://main.d2qwcljsqlxhuc.amplifyapp.com/

A full-stack health insurance web application built with React, Express and MongoDB. The features include, user authentication, contact form and payment integration.

The database and Users collection were created successfully using MongoDB atlas. NodeJS was connected to MongoDB using Mongoose, a MongoDB object modeling tool designed to work in an asynchronous environment.

A "users" model was created which tells the database how to store data that a user passes. The app has register and login endpoints, allowing users to register and login to the application from the frontend.

Users are able to purchase policies online using Paystack payment.

The contact form data is processed by Node.js backend and an email is sent to the administrator.

The Node.js backend is deployed on Heroku. The React frontend is deployed in AWS Cloud.

- Developed custom WordPress powered e-commerce and non-ecommerce websites.
- Customized WordPress themes and plugins to the specification clients.
- Built easily extensible and update-safe child themes, thereby speeding up website development time.
- Created a Task management application with Vue.js.

The following are links to some of the websites and web applications I developed;

Jade Event Hub: https://ja-de.co/

WebPro Media: https:/webpromedia.com.ng/

Banji Adesanmi Ministry (http://banjiadesanmiministry.org/)

The NFVF: https://www.nfvf.co.za/

Auracool Digital (http://auracooldigital.com/)
VVM Energy: https://vvmgroup.co/energy/
Stockmatik (https://www.stockmatik.com/)
StockPro: (https://www.stockpro.vercel.app/

EASYWARE

Lagos, Nigeria Feb 2020 - Present

Full Stack Developer (Part-time)

NGO Website:

Developed an NGO website with PHP and MySQL where the site visitors can make financial donations online to causes of their choice. This was done by integrating PayPal and Paystack payment gateways APIs.

- Hospital Management Web Application:
 - Collaborated with my team members to work on a web-based hospital management system using PHP, MySQL and Ajax technology. The application accumulates and integrates data from all departments to automate the hospital's daily internal processes.
- Human Resources Management Web Application:
 Collaborated with my team members to work on a human resources web application using PHP, MySQL and Ajax technology. It combines a number of functions to ensure the easy management of human resources, business processes and data.
- Bug Fixing
 Tested software for bugs, fixed bugs and documenting processes to increase efficiency.

ELLAE CREATIVE DIGITAL BRANDING AGENCY

Senior Web Developer

Lagos, Nigeria Nov 2015 – Sept 2016

 Union Bank Internet Banking Web Application: https://uniononline.unionbankng.com/OnlineBanking/

Developed a rich user interface for Union Bank internet banking platform.

The aim of the project was to provide a comprehensive, integrated, interoperable, and modular solution that enables Union Bank to manage evolving customer expectations. The functional implementation of the interface was developed with the popular front-end development framework, Bootstrap, which was extensively customized.

- Union Bank Desktop Application (Bank of The Future App)
 Developed the user interface using a combination of Metro UI and Bootstrap.
- Rebuilt Union Bank Windows Form Quiz Application:
 The quiz application is a rich client desktop application built with Windows Forms
 (Winforms) library and Visual Basic [.Net] (VB.Net). The application makes us of standard controls as well as DevExpress UI controls which are powered by a patent-pending server-side data processing engine.

WEBPRO MEDIA

Lagos, Nigeria

Web Developer

Ian 2014 – Oct 2015

Web Developer

Jan 2014 – Oct 2015

Developed visually appealing and functional custom WordPress newgred a commerce and

- Developed visually appealing and functional custom WordPress powered e-commerce and non-ecommerce websites to the satisfaction of clients.
- Customized several WordPress themes and plugins in order to suit the specific needs of clients.
- Built easily extensible and update-safe child themes, thereby speeding up website development time.

Some of the website developed during this period include the following;

PTV Phones – Ecommerce - http://ptvphones.com/
Mundoherald – Blog/News - http://mundoherald.com/
Banji Adesanmi Ministry – Online Ministry/Non Profit - http://banjiadesanmiministry.org/

JOBBERMAN LIMITED Lagos, Nigeria

User Interface Developer, Smarty Template Designer

Jul 2013 - Dec 2014

 Developed and deployed several appealing designs and user friendly interfaces for the applicant and employer areas of the Jobberman website which contributed considerably to the increase in the number of sign-ups.

• Created and modified web pages using a combination Smarty Template Engine and the Bootstrap CSS framework which proved effective for facilitating a speedy development.

WEB THINKERS LIMITED

Lagos, Nigeria

Web Designer/Developer, WordPress Developer

Oct 2012 - Jun 2013

- Developed websites using the latest web technologies such as HTML5 and CSS3 with minimum supervision.
- Supervised junior web designers.
- Completed advanced training on how the WordPress content management system can be used to build easily updated websites, online forums and social networking websites

HERITECH NETWORKS LIMITED

Lagos, Nigeria

Web Designer, Graphics Designer

Oct 2011 – May 2012

- Singlehandedly built a new website for the company.
- Designed and developed several websites and rich internet applications that were satisfactory to the clients and the management team.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

NIIT Akwaibom/Lagos, Nigeria
Developing Professional Web Pages Using Adobe Dreamweaver Sep 2010 – May 2011
Rich Content Creation Using Adobe Flash Sep 2010 – May 2011

NYSC Akwaibom/Lagos, Nigeria *Certificate of National Service Mar 9 2010 – Feb 8 2011*

BSc Cell Biology & Genetics Lagos, Nigeria
University of Lagos 2003/2004 - 2007/2008

SSCELagos, NigeriaJextoban Secondary School2000 – 2001Greensprings Secondary School1995 - 2000

COURSES AND TRAININGS

- Development Of Professional Web Pages In Adobe Dreamweaver
- Rich Content Creation Using Adobe Flash
- Responsive Website Design/Development
- Rich Internet Applications(RIA) Development
- WordPress Development
- E-commerce Development

HOBBIES

Listening to music, reading, watching movies, physical exercise, sports